♪〜
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original
Interviews with Monster Girls
The class is astir
I want to let myself go too,
But I end up putting on a fake smile.
Your eyes alone conveyed a competitive spirit
Biting at your lip forcefully.
You once said,
"I wouldn't want to worry what someone thinks
And end up hurting someone else in the process!"
When the chime rings out, as the rain lifts up,
We'll pass the boundaries of our school!
Jumping through the puddles, light will scatter about
Our smiles, and wishes will be so bright!
I want to talk...
About your Wonderful Original!
〜♪
Takahashi Tetsuo Wants to Protect
Oh, her?
（井森(いもり)）
あいつか〜 あいつさ
She's...
調子に乗る[ちょうしにのる]:to be elated/to be excited|to get up to speed
ちょっと調子に乗ってない？
kinda arrogant, don't you think?
（雪(ゆき)）うっ…
I admit she is cute,
認める[したためる]:to write up, 認める[みとめる]:to recognize|to deem|to approve||
（井森）
かわいいのは認めるけどさ
but she could hang out with him once, at least.
遊び[あそび]:playing|play (margin between on and off, gap before pressing button or lever has an effect), くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
遊びくらい
行ってやってもいいのに
Maybe she thinks she's some kind of idol...
アイドル:young star/young entertainer/heartthrob
（木村(きむら)）
アイドルにでも
なったつもりなのかね
ハア…
あっ
Biology Prep Room
Kusakabe?
（高橋(たかはし)）日下部(くさかべ)？
（雪）はっ
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
たっ… 高橋先生
M-Mr. Takahashi...
What's wrong?
（高橋）どうした？
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|
じ… 実は 自分が その
I-It's just... I heard people...
s-saying mean things... about me.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
わっ… 悪く言われているのを
聞いてしまって
そうか
I see.
Well, this isn't the place to talk about it.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
ここで話しててもなんだから
話は中で…
Let's go inside.
Is it because I'm a demi?!
（雪）私がデミだからですかね？
（高橋）えっ？
If I weren't a demi,
（雪）私がデミでなければ
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
こんな気持ちには…
I wouldn't feel like this...
（高橋）
大丈夫だ それは違う
それは違うぞ 日下部
Don't worry. That's not true.
That isn't true, Kusakabe.
Mr. Takahashi...
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（雪）高橋先生…
（氷の粒が落ちた音）
（高橋）ん？
あっ…
I have to protect her.
守る[まもる]:to protect/to guard|to keep (i.e. a promise)
（高橋）
守らねばなるまい
デミちゃんを守らねば
I have to protect this demi!
Generally speaking,
一般的[いっぱんてき]:popular/typical/general, 陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student, 些細[ささい]:trivial/slight, 悩み[なやみ]:trouble/troubles/worry
（高橋）
一般的にいえば 陰口など
女子高生にありがちな些細(ささい)な悩みだ
gossip is a trivial issue, common among high school girls.
以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||
だが 彼女がデミである以上
But since she's a demi,
this particular issue isn't quite that simple.
単純[たんじゅん]:simplicity/simple/uncomplicated, 片づける[かたづける]:to tidy up|to settle (problem)|to finish||
それは単純に
片づけられるものではないだろう
Hikari and Machi have accepted that, and are living normally enough...
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, 町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something, 受け入れる[うけいれる]:to accept/to receive/to agree, 生活[せいかつ]:living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood
ひかりや町(まち)なんかは
受け入れて生活してるからな
（早紀絵(さきえ)）あっ
（高橋）ん？
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（高橋）あっ 佐藤(さとう)先生
Ms. Satou?
アジサイ:bigleaf hydrangea (Hydrangea macrophylla)/French hydrangea
（高橋）アジサイですか？
Hydrangeas, eh?
庭[にわ]:garden/yard|field (of action), たくさん:a lot/lots|enough, 咲く[さく]:to bloom, せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare
（早紀絵）
庭に たくさん咲いていたので
せっかくですし
There were lots of them in the garden,
so I borrowed a few.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 仕事[しごと]:work/job|work
高橋先生は お仕事ですか？
Are you working, Mr. Takahashi?
天気[てんき]:weather/the elements|fair weather, 薄暗い[うすぐらい]:dim/gloomy, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, 室[しつ]:room|wife (of someone of high rank)|scabbard|, 室[むろ]:greenhouse/icehouse/cellar, 籠もる[こもる]:to shut oneself in (e.g. one's room)|to be filled with (emotion, enthusiasm, etc.)|to fill the room (of a gas, smell, etc.)||, ばかり:only/merely|approximately
（高橋）
ハハッ こんな天気で
薄暗い準備室に籠もってばかりだと
Yes, with the weather like this,
staying in that dark prep room is depressing.
気がめいる[きがめいる]:to feel depressed/to be down
気がめいりますからね
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding
（早紀絵）
あの…
私 高橋先生を誤解してました
Um... I was wrong about you, Mr. Takahashi.
（高橋）え？
Huh?
The thing with Machi's backpack...
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, リュック:rucksack/knapsack/backpack, 通学[つうがく]:commuting to school/school commute, 件[くだん]:the aforementioned/the said|the usual, 件[けん]:matter/case/item
（早紀絵）
町さんのリュック通学の件
I happened to hear you asking the principal to help.
校長[こうちょう]:principal/headmaster, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother, たまたま:casually/unexpectedly/accidentally
校長先生に お願いしていたのを
たまたま聞いてまして
Oh, that—
（高橋）ああ あれは…
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 対する[たいする]:to face (each other)|to be directed toward (the future, etc.)|to receive (a client, etc.)||, 優しい[やさしい]:tender/kind/gentle, 気遣い[きづかい]:consideration/concern/fear, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
（早紀絵）
高橋先生はデミに対して
優しい気遣いをするような方なのに
Even though you're someone so considerate of demis,
ったら:indicates supposition/if ... then|(typically after someone's name) indicates exasperation, 入学式[にゅうがくしき]:school entrance ceremony, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 態度をとる[たいどをとる]:to take an attitude, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
私ったら入学式の準備のときには
あんな態度をとってしまって
on the day of the opening ceremony, I behaved that way toward you!
I'm so sorry!
すみませんでした！
（高橋）
ああ いえ
あのときは自分のほうこそ
Oh, not at all!
I should be the one to apologize for being insensitive to your situation.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||, 無神経[むしんけい]:insensitive/inconsiderate/callous
先生のご事情も考えず
無神経だったと
As for the backpack, Hikari...
リュック:rucksack/knapsack/backpack, 件[くだん]:the aforementioned/the said|the usual, 件[けん]:matter/case/item, ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray
それに リュックの件は ひかり…
Takanashi asked me to help.
頼む[たのむ]:to request|to call|to entrust to|
小鳥遊(たかなし)から頼まれたんです
Takanashi? The older sister, you mean?
お姉さん[おねえさん]:elder sister|(vocative) young lady|miss (referring to a waitress, etc.)||
小鳥遊さん…
ってお姉さんのほうの？
Yeah.
身近[みぢか]:near oneself/close to one/familiar, 接する[せっする]:to touch|to receive (e.g. visitor)|to receive (news)||, ながら:while/during|while
（高橋）
ええ あの子たちと
身近に接していながら
I work so closely with those girls,
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 気付く[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
結局
何も気付いてやれてないんですよ
but I didn't notice anything.
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 理解[りかい]:understanding/comprehension/appreciation
もっと あの子たちのことを
理解したいと
I want to understand them better, but...
思ってはいるのですが…
Um, Mr. Takahashi?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（早紀絵）あの 先生
Yes?
（高橋）はい？
Um...
協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration, いただける:to be able to receive/to be able to take|to be able to eat
（早紀絵）
その… 私も協力させて
いただけませんでしょうか？
C-Can I be of any help at all?
（高橋）え？
Huh?
I'm a demi, after all!
私 デミですから！
身[み]:body|oneself|one's place|, 身[むくろ]:(dead) body/corpse, しっかり:tightly (holding on)/firmly|strongly (built)
ああ ええ それは もう
この身でしっかり…
Yes, I've experienced that firsthand.
ああっ…
I mean...
教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom), でもある:to also be (formal, literary)/implies that as well as the earlier stated this is also the case|to be ... or something
（早紀絵）
きょ… 教師でもありますし
A-And I'm also a teacher!
生徒[せいと]:pupil, 悩み[なやみ]:trouble/troubles/worry
デミの生徒の悩みなら
I have a duty to address the concerns of my demi students!
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 手伝い[てつだい]:helper/assistant|help, 義務[ぎむ]:duty/obligation/responsibility
私も 一緒にお手伝いする
義務というか
意味[いみ]:meaning/significance, 含める[ふくめる]:to include (in a group or scope)|to instruct|to include (a nuance)||, 協力[きょうりょく]:cooperation/collaboration
そういう意味も含めまして
協力できると！
With that in mind, I really think I can help!
ハア ハア ハア…
しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
（早紀絵）
しまった！
Oops.
願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
いや…
それは願ってもないことですよ
No, I think that sounds perfect...
I'd appreciate your help.
願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
ぜひ お願いします
やった〜！　フフッ
All right!
（高橋）ハア〜
So, the students who said mean things about Kusakabe...
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 生徒[せいと]:pupil
（高橋）
その 日下部を悪く言っていた
生徒なんですが
It seems they constantly gossip about others as well.
常習[じょうしゅう]:custom/common practice/habit, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target, 陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back
どうやら 常習的に
人の陰口を言っているようなんです
Then, Kusakabe wasn't being specifically targeted?
特に[とくに]:particularly/especially, 限る[かぎる]:to restrict/to limit|to be restricted to
（早紀絵）
じゃあ 特に日下部さんに
限ったことではないんですね
Probably not.
多分[たぶん]:perhaps/probably|generous
（高橋）多分
But she's convinced that it's because she's a demi?
（早紀絵）
でも 彼女は
“自分がデミだから”と
思い込む[おもいこむ]:to be under impression that/to be convinced that/to imagine that, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
思い込んでしまった
（高橋）うん
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
佐藤先生は どう思いますか？
What do you think, Ms. Satou?
Even without considering the gossip,
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 以前[いぜん]:ago/since/before
（早紀絵）
陰口のこと以前に 日下部さん
Kusakabe seems to avoid contact with other people, to begin with.
接触[せっしょく]:touch/contact, 極力[きょくりょく]:to the utmost/to the best of one's ability, 避ける[さける, よける]:to avoid (physical contact with)|to avoid (situation)|to ward off, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife)
いつも 人との接触を
極力 避けてるように見えるんです
I mean, in a different way than I do.
意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
その… 私とは違う意味で
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
（高橋）
確かに そんな感じはありますね
Yeah, I noticed that, too.
事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
彼女には
何か事情があるのかもしれません
Maybe she has some reason.
A reason.
事情[じじょう]:circumstances/consideration/conditions, 家庭的[かていてき]:family-oriented/familial
事情… 家庭的なこととか？
You mean something like her family?
I have a feeling it's more connected to her nature as a demi.
性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 由来[ゆらい]:origin/source/history, 気がする[きがする]:to have a certain mood or feeling/to have a hunch
（早紀絵）
というより デミの性質に
由来するような気がするんです
Her nature?
性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition
性質ですか？
The reason I had the wrong idea about you
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
（早紀絵）
私が高橋先生を
誤解してしまったのも
性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition
サキュバスの性質のため
was because my succubus nature made me overly self-conscious.
自意識[じいしき]:self-consciousness, 過剰[かじょう]:excess/surplus/over-, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
自意識過剰に
なってしまったからですし
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 見方[みかた]:viewpoint/point of view|way of understanding
（高橋）なるほど そういう見方も
I see... There's that way of looking at it.
She probably doesn't have anyone to talk to about it,
恐らく[おそらく]:perhaps/likely/probably, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.)
（早紀絵）
恐らく
相談相手もいないでしょうし
なおさら:still more/even more|still less, 折り合い[おりあい]:agreement (e.g. business, dispute)/compromise|mutual relations (e.g. between parents and child, coworkers, etc.), にくい:hateful/abominable|amazing, にくい:difficult to .../hard to ...
なおさら デミとしての折り合いが
つけにくいのではないでしょうか
which makes it even harder to come to terms with her demi identity.
やっぱり:too/also|still, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 声かけ[こえかけ]:saying something (to someone)/greeting/approaching (someone)
ハア〜 やっぱり
もっと早く声かけとくんだったな
I guess I should have tried to talk to her sooner...
あの 私のほうから
聞いてみましょうか？
Well, why don't I try to speak to her?
えっ？
Talking to another demi might be easier for her.
同士[どうし, どし]:fellow/mutual/companion, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
デミ同士なら
話しやすいでしょうし
That would be a big help.
助かる[たすかる]:to be saved|to escape harm|to be helped
それは助かります
I'm really glad you're on this with me.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
佐藤先生がいてくれて
よかったですよ
とんでも:unthinkable/unexpected/outrageous
ととと… とんでもないです！
N-N-N-Not at all! It's just what any teacher ought to do!
くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that, 教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom), 当然[とうぜん]:natural/as a matter of course/justified
それくらい
教師としては当然ですので
フォロー:follow
日下部のフォローも
そうなんですが
Talking to Kusakabe is important...
えっ？
But we should also do something about the students who were gossiping.
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 生徒[せいと]:pupil
陰口を言っていた
生徒たちのことも…
You're right.
そうですね
ただ言うなというだけでは…
Telling them to stop won't work.
They don't want people to know they feel inferior,
劣等感[れっとうかん]:inferiority complex, ごまかす:to deceive/to falsify|to dodge
（高橋）劣等感をごまかしたい
面と向かう[めんとむかう]:to meet face-to-face, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
かといって
面と向かって言うのは怖い
but they're afraid to face their victims.
I believe that mental weakness
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 心理[しんり]:state of mind/mentality/psychology
陰口を言う心理は
弱い[よわい]:weak/frail/delicate
そういった心の弱さから
来るものだと思います
is what makes people gossip about others.
If possible,
できれば 彼女たちに
I'd like them to realize that they don't have to rely on gossip.
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 逃げる[にげる]:to escape/to run away, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
陰口に逃げない心を
持ってほしいんです
Yes.
ええ
Maybe it would be unfair to expect that from high school students...
高校生[こうこうせい]:senior high school student, 求める[もとめる]:to want|to request|to seek|, 酷[こく]:severe/harsh/stringent, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
高校生に それを求めるのは
酷な話ですかね
Now, what to do?
（高橋）さて どうしたもんか
Takanashi, wait a minute.
（雪）
小鳥遊さん！
ちょっと待ってよ
（高橋）ん？
（雪）
ねえ どこに行くの？
ちょっと… 小鳥遊さん
Hey, where are we going?
Hey, Takanashi...
小鳥遊さん！
Takanashi!
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray
ひかり
Hikari?
And they just left it like that.
そのまま:without change/as it is|just like
（木村）そのままにしたんだって
No way! That's crazy!
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific, じゃん:isn't it
（井森）それ ヤバいじゃん
笑い声[わらいごえ]:laughter
（２人の笑い声）
Also, I heard the physics teacher, Iwai, is being sent to another school.
小鳥遊さん…
Takanashi...
文句[もんく]:complaint/grumbling|phrase
（ひかり）
ユッキー
私 あいつらに文句言いに行くから
Yukki, I'm going to give them a piece of my mind.
Really? Why?
ユッキーは
ここで待って聞いてて
You wait here and listen.
It seems like he got involved in some risky stuff.
えっ…
What the hell?
I'll let you decide what happens afterward.
任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||
そのあと どうするかは
ユッキーに任せるから
With that face, maybe it can't be helped.
You think he went after someone?
No way. He wouldn't have the guts.
ヘタレ:incompetence/laziness/worthlessness
（木村）
んなことできないでしょ
ヘタレだし
かっこ:every one/each, かっこ:firm/unshakeable/resolute
（井森）かっこわる〜
（木村）ハハハッ
What a loser!
（２人）ん？
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 組[くみ]:set (of items)|group (of people)|typesetting
（木村）あんた 確か Ｂ組の…
Aren't you from class B?
バンパイア:vampire
（井森）ああ バンパイアの
（木村）小鳥遊…
Oh, the vampire.
Takanashi...
Is trashing people behind their backs all you ever do?
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, ばっかり:only/merely|approximately
あんたたち
人の陰口ばっかり言ってるんでしょ
Give it a rest.
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
やめなよ そういうの
ああ？
Huh?
Oh, is this about Kusakabe?
あ〜 何？　日下部のこと？
（木村）ああ〜
As a fellow demi, you're out to avenge her?
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 弔う[とむらう, とぶらう]:to mourn for/to condole with (family, etc.)|to hold a memorial service (for), 合戦[かっせん]:battle/fight/fighting, かっこいい:attractive/good-looking/stylish
同じデミだから弔い合戦ってわけ
かっこいい…
That's cool of—
No!
（ひかり）違う！
（２人）あっ…
Yes, Yukki is a demi, but it doesn't matter!
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||
（ひかり）
確かにユッキーはデミだけど
関係ない！
文句を言う[もんくをいう]:to complain/to make a complaint
あんたたちに文句を言うのは
I'm giving you two a piece of my mind
文句を言う[もんくをいう]:to complain/to make a complaint
あんたたちに
文句を言いたいからよ
because that's what I want to do!
相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), あおる:to fan (oneself, flames, etc.)|to flap/to be shaken (by wind), あおる:to gulp down (a drink)/to slurp, はぐらかす:to dodge/to evade/to give the slip
相手をあおって
はぐらかそうとするな！
Don't try to dodge it by provoking me!
If you don't want to stop blabbing about people, then fine...
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
別に陰口を言うのを
やめたくなかったら それでもいい
でも あんたたちが言ってるのを
見たり聞いたりしたら
But every time I see or hear you doing it,
I'll call you on it.
度[たび, たんび]:time (three times, each time, etc.)/times, 度[ど]:degree (angle, temperature, scale, etc.)|counter for occurrences and times|strength (of alcohol), 文句を言う[もんくをいう]:to complain/to make a complaint
その度に 文句を言いに行くから
If you want to hang around and badmouth people,
のんびり:carefree/at leisure, 他人[たにん, ひと]:another person|unrelated person (i.e. not related by blood)|outsider, 悪口を言う[わるくちをいう]:to insult/to say something insulting about/to bad-mouth, 耳に入る[みみにはいる]:to hear of, 所[ところ, とこ]:place|address|district||, 所[しょ]:counter for places
のんびり他人(ひと)の悪口を言いたいなら
私の目や耳に入らない所でやって
you'd better do it where I can't find you.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
あっ 先生…
Mr. Takahashi...
We aren't the only ones who talk about people behind their backs.
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us, じゃん:isn't it
（木村）
別に陰口言ってるのって
私たちだけじゃねえじゃん
私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us, 文句[もんく]:complaint/grumbling|phrase
なんで私たちだけ文句…
Why single us out?
（ひかり）あんたたちだけじゃない
It won't be just you two.
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, 見聞き[みきき]:information/experience/observation, 文句を言う[もんくをいう]:to complain/to make a complaint
陰口を言っている人を見聞きしたら
誰にだって 私は文句を言う
I'll give a piece of my mind to anyone I catch badmouthing someone else!
躍起[やっき]:desperation/eagerness
なんで そんなに躍起になるんだよ
Why are you so gung-ho about this?
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
陰口言うなんて
誰でもやってるだろ
Everyone talks about people behind their backs.
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 理屈[りくつ]:theory/reason, 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear
みんながやってるから
なんて理屈 私は嫌い！
I can't stand the excuse that "everyone does it"!
傷つける[きずつける]:to wound|to hurt someone's feelings (pride, etc.)|to damage, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|
みんな
傷つけ合ってるから
Everyone hurts people,
傷つける[きずつける]:to wound|to hurt someone's feelings (pride, etc.)|to damage, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
私も傷つけていいなんて
so you think you're allowed to hurt people?
口にする[くちにする]:to taste/to eat|to speak of, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
口にして
恥ずかしくないの？
Aren't you ashamed to say that?
No one in the world likes being badmouthed!
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back, うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
陰口を言われて
うれしい人なんているわけないのに
What, so you never talk about anyone behind their back?
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back
（木村）
じゃあ なに
あんたは人の陰口言わないの？
ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions, 全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, 直接[ちょくせつ]:direct/immediate/personal
（ひかり）
言わない 言いたいことがあれば
全部 直接言う
No. If I want to say something, I say it to their face.
言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say
言えなければ 言わない
If I can't, I say nothing.
陰口をたたく[かげぐちをたたく]:to backbite
（井森）
そうすれば
自分は陰口をたたかれないとでも？
You think that will keep people from talking about you?
（ひかり）それはない
No, I don't.
I know as soon as I leave,
去る[さる]:to leave|to pass|to be distant||, 陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back
だって 私がここを去ったあと
２人は私の陰口を言うでしょ？
you two will start griping about me.
（２人）あっ…
Sorry.
（ひかり）ごめん
（２人）ん？
言い方[いいかた]:way of talking/speaking style, 意地悪[いじわる]:malicious/ill-tempered/unkind
（ひかり）
その 今の言い方は意地悪だった
It was mean of me to say it that way.
（井森）は？　えっ うん…
Huh? Er, s-sure...
陰口[かげぐち]:malicious gossip/backbiting/speaking ill behind someone's back
（ひかり）
陰口を言わない人も
陰口を言われると思う
I know people who don't badmouth others still get badmouthed.
むしろ:rather/better/instead, むしろ:woven mat (esp. one made of straw)|seat, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
むしろ
言われやすいんじゃないかな？
In fact, they're probably the easiest targets.
決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
（ひかり）でも 決めたんだ
（２人）うん？
But I've made up my mind!
It's just for my satisfaction, but...
自己満足[じこまんぞく]:self-satisfaction/(self-)complacency/smugness
ただの自己満足だけど
Even if people say mean things about me, I won't do anything I'll regret!
後ろめたい[うしろめたい]:feeling guilty/having a guilty conscience, 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left
私は人から言われても
後ろめたさが残ることはしないって
はっ
泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob
あんた 泣いて…
Are you... crying?
Sorry, I've said what I wanted to say.
（ひかり）
ごめん
言いたいこと言ったから
I'll go now.
もう行くから
I can't agree with what you said,
納得[なっとく]:consent/assent|understanding
（木村）
あんたが言ったこと
納得はできないけどさ
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
なんか すごいって思ったよ
but I am kinda impressed.
Still, why would you say all that?
でも どうして そこまで…
約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny
（ひかり）
約束したから
Because I promised...
妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, 約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny
妹と約束したから
I promised my sister.
Your sister?
妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend
（木村）妹？
（井森）小鳥遊ひま…
Takanashi Hima—
（２人）あっ
Ku...
（木村）くっ…
（井森）日下部
Kusakabe...
なさる:to do
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
（２人）え？
（雪）私 その…
I, um...
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 体質[たいしつ]:constitution (physical)/genetic make-up|structure (e.g. of an organization), 疑問[ぎもん]:question/problem/doubt
実は 自分のデミの体質に
疑問があって
The truth is, my demi nature still bothers me,
接する[せっする]:to touch|to receive (e.g. visitor)|to receive (news)||, 避ける[さける, よける]:to avoid (physical contact with)|to avoid (situation)|to ward off
それでちょっと
人と接するのを避けてて
so I've always avoided contact with people.
不快[ふかい]:displeasure/discomfort|indisposition, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense
それが
不快に感じたようだったら
If that gave you a bad impression,
well... I'm sorry.
なさる:to do
その… ごめんなさい
謝る[あやまる]:to apologize/to apologise
（木村）なんで あんたが謝るのよ
Why are you apologizing?
私たち[わたしたち, わたくしたち]:we/us
（井森）私たちこそ
We're the ones who should...
ごめん
Sorry.
うっ…
Wha—
上がる[あがる]:to rise|to enter (esp. from outdoors)|to enter (a school)||
（ひかり）なっ…
（高橋）上がってるぞ
The rain stopped.
ちょっ…
You—
You hungry? I'll treat you to something.
腹[はら]:abdomen|womb|one's mind||, 減る[へる]:to decrease (in size or number)/to diminish/to abate, 飯[めし]:cooked rice|meal|one's livelihood, 飯[まんま, まま]:cooked rice, おごる:to give (someone) a treat|to be extravagant/to live luxuriously
（高橋）
腹減ってないか？
何か飯でも おごってやろうか？
痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding
（ひかり）痛(い)たた…
Ow, ow, ow!
髪[かみ]:hair (on the head), 結う[ゆう, いう]:to do up (hair)/to braid/to fasten, なでる:to stroke/to caress|to comb (hair), 痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding
もう 髪結ったとこ なでたら痛い！
It hurts when you rub my head where my hair's tied up!
なでる:to stroke/to caress|to comb (hair), 後ろ[うしろ]:back/behind/rear
（高橋）すまん すまん
（ひかり）なでるなら後ろ！
Sorry about that.
If you're gonna rub it, rub the back!
I'm home.
ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently, おかえり:return|welcome home
（ひかり）ただいま〜
（ひまり）おかえり
Welcome back.
うわあ:Wow!/Holy smokes!/Aaargh!
（ひかり）おっりゃ〜！
（ひまり）うわあ〜！
（ひかり）フフッ
（ひまり）は？
Huh?
（ひかり）いいから
Don't ask.
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||
（ひまり）なっ… 何なのよ 急に
Wh-Where'd this come from?
Don't ask.
（ひかり）いいから
Did something happen at school?
学校[がっこう]:school
（ひまり）学校で何かあった？
（ひかり）うん 大丈夫
No, I'm fine.
Interviews with Monster Girls
Audiovisual Room
The thing is, a student came to talk to me recently...
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 先日[せんじつ]:the other day/a few days ago, とある:a certain ..., とある:according to/reads/reading, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
（高橋）
実は先日
とある生徒に相談されてだな
それについて
俺に思うところがあって
I had my own thoughts about it, so I called you all here.
集まる[あつまる]:to gather/to collect/to assemble, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
みんなに集まってもらったわけだ
Ms. Satou, too.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
佐藤先生にもな
相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
（町）
えっ 相談？
私はしてませんが…
Someone talked to you? It wasn't me.
（ひかり）私でもないもん
Me, either.
（２人）あっ…
下手くそ[へたくそ, ヘタクソ]:shitty/clumsy/poor
（高橋）お前ら 下手くそか
Can't you guys be more sensitive?
すっ すみません…
S-Sorry.
W-We couldn't help it! There's only three of us here!
しかたない:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use, じゃん:isn't it, もともと:originally/by nature/from the start, 択[たく]:counter for choices, options, etc.
しし… しかたないじゃん
もともと３択だし
（高橋のせきばらい）
フフッ
（高橋）とにかくだ
Anyway, I know there are many things demis might worry about now.
いろいろ:various|various colors (colours), 悩みを抱える[なやみをかかえる]:to have troubles/to have concerns, やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
デミが いろいろと
悩みを抱えやすいことが分かった
互い[たがい]:mutual/reciprocal, 積極的[せっきょくてき]:positive/assertive/active
お前たちには 互いに積極的に
I'd like for you three to be able to help each other out.
相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, 合える[あえる]:to dress (vegetables, salad, etc.)
相談し合えるように
なってほしいと思っている
You three are the only demi students at this school.
学校[がっこう]:school, 生徒[せいと]:pupil
この学校で
デミの生徒は３人だけだ
I'd like you to treasure that link among you.
つながり:connection/link/relationship, 大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play
そのつながりを大切にしてほしい
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, にくい:hateful/abominable|amazing, にくい:difficult to .../hard to ..., ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 頼る[たよる]:to rely on/to have recourse to/to depend on
友達に聞きにくいことがあれば
俺や佐藤先生を頼ってくれ
If you can't confide in your friends, you can come to me or Ms. Satou.
In particular, Ms. Satou, is a demi, like you, as well as a woman.
特に[とくに]:particularly/especially, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender
特に佐藤先生は
みんなと同じデミであり女性だ
心強い[こころづよい]:heartening/reassuring, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
こんなに心強い方はいないぞ
There's no one you can trust more.
相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, 側[そば, そく]:near/close|third person, 側[がわ, かわ]:side (of something, or taking someone's side)/part|(watch) case
私も相談する側のほうが…
はっ！
I'd rather be the one seeking advice from—
遠慮[えんりょ]:reserve|declining|forethought, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
ああっ…
私にも遠慮なく相談してね
F-Feel free to talk to me anytime, too!
（高橋）
言いたかったのは それだけだ
That's all I wanted to say.
実際[じっさい]:practicality|reality|bhutakoti (limit of reality), 集まる[あつまる]:to gather/to collect/to assemble, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
実際に みんなで集まって
話したんだということで
I hope you're aware that getting together to discuss things like this is important.
大事[だいじ, おおごと]:important/valuable|safe (Tochigi dialect), 認識[にんしき]:recognition/awareness/perception, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me), うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
大事なことなんだと
認識してもらえるとうれしい
Does anyone have anything they'd like to talk about right now?
取り急ぎ[とりいそぎ]:in haste, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
取り急ぎ 何か相談したいことが
あるヤツはいるか？
急[きゅう]:urgent|sharp|rapid||, 思いつく[おもいつく]:to think of/to hit upon|to remember
まあ 急には思いつかんか
I guess you can't think of anything right now.
辺[へん]:area|side|circumstances, 辺[へ, べ]:surrounding area|shore (of the sea)|suffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc.
じゃあ 今日は この辺で…
That'll be all for today, then—
（ひかり）はい！
（高橋）ん？
Me!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
私 まだ先生に
ハグしてもらってません
I haven't gotten a hug from you yet!
（高橋）は？
（早紀絵）ハグ？
Huh?
Hug?
（ひかり）おりゃ〜！
Hi-yah!
ぎゅう:cattle (Bos taurus)/cow|beef, ぎゅう:pimp/brothel tout
ぎゅう〜
Squeeze...
アハハ:a-ha-ha (laughing loudly)
（ひかり）エヘヘッ
（高橋）アハハ 何？
Hee hee.
Ha ha... What?
（ひかり）エヘヘヘッ
（高橋）アハハハ だから何？
Hee hee hee!
Ha ha ha. Seriously, what?
（町）はっ！　私もいいですか？
（高橋）え？
C-Can I have one, too?
Huh?
Sure.
（高橋）はい
（町）わぷぷっ…
Thank you.
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, ござる:to be
（町）ありがとうございます
（高橋）いえ…
No problem.
（ひかり）よかったね マッチー
（町）うん
Good for you, Macchi!
Yep.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（早紀絵）高橋先生
（高橋）は？
Mr. Takahashi...
ウフッ
I'll take one, too—
ついで:next/secondly/subsequently, ついで:opportunity/occasion
ついでに私も！
No, that's a bad idea...
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger
（高橋）いや それは さすがに…
（早紀絵）そうですよね
You're right.
○Ｘ＄＃％□…
ああ どうだ？
日下部も よかったら…
Uh...
How about it, Kusakabe? If you'd like one, too...
While we're at it.
流れ[ながれ]:stream/current|course of events
（高橋）流れで
（雪）えっ？
Huh?
流れ[ながれ]:stream/current|course of events
（早紀絵）ええ〜！
（町･ひかり）流れ？
While you're at it?!
Kusakabe...
（高橋）日下部
無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||, 悩み[なやみ]:trouble/troubles/worry, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
無理に悩みを話せとは言わない
I won't force you to talk about what's troubling you.
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light)
さっきも言ったとおり
Like I said before,
I believe it's fate that you're in an environment
囲む[かこむ, かごむ]:to surround|to besiege|to play (go, shogi, etc.), 環境[かんきょう]:environment/circumstance
お前が ほかのデミたちに
囲まれた環境にあることは
きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 縁[ゆかり]:related to (some person or place)/affinity/connection, 縁[えん, えにし]:fate|relationship (e.g. between two people)|family ties||
きっと何かの縁だと思う
where you're surrounded by other demis.
うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious, 言える[いえる]:to be possible to say/to be able to say, きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 良い[よい]:good|sufficient (can be used to turn down an offer)|profitable (e.g. deal, business offer, etc.)|, 必ず[かならず]:always/without exception/necessarily, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun
だから うまく言えないが
きっと良くなる 必ず楽しくなる
So... I can't say it well, but I'm sure it'll get better.
You will have fun.
So don't worry.
安心[あんしん]:relief/peace of mind, 安心[あんじん]:obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice
だから 安心しろ なっ
Okay?
（雪）はい
Yes.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
先生！　先生！
Mr. Takahashi, Mr. Takahashi!
あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair), くださる:to give/to confer|to kindly do for one
この子にも
ハグしてあげてください
Give her a hug, too!
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||
（高橋）
“この子”って それ 町だろ
Her? But that's Machi.
流れ[ながれ]:stream/current|course of events, まったく:really/truly|indeed
（ひかり）流れ 流れ
（高橋）まったく…
Just while you're at it!
Sheesh... Is that all right, Machi?
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||
（高橋）いいのか？　町
（町）あっ はい
Uh, sure.
All right, then...
（高橋）よいしょっと
はあっ！
辺[へん]:area|side|circumstances, 辺[へ, べ]:surrounding area|shore (of the sea)|suffix used as a rough indicator of location, direction, time, etc.
えっ じゃっ…
じゃ 今日は この辺で
Well, that'll be all for today.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 奇声[きせい]:strange voice, 一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（早紀絵）
高橋先生 今の奇声は 一体！
Mr. Takahashi, what was that weird scream?!
一体[いったい]:...the heck (e.g. "what the heck?")|one object|one form||
（雪）
一体 何があったんですか？
What happened?
Wait! I have a question!
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
（ひかり）
先生 待って 相談！
リアクション:reaction, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
今のリアクションの
意味について 相談を…
I want to know what that reaction meant!
He called all the demis together for a meeting?
集める[あつめる]:to collect/to assemble/to gather, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, 会[え]:gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.), 会[かい]:meeting/assembly|association
（ひまり）デミを集めて相談会？
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 放課後[ほうかご]:after school, 視聴覚[しちょうかく]:senses of seeing and hearing/audiovisual, 室[しつ]:room|wife (of someone of high rank)|scabbard|, 室[むろ]:greenhouse/icehouse/cellar
（悠子(ゆうこ)）
うん 高橋先生が
放課後に視聴覚室で
Yeah, Mr. Takahashi had them meet in the AV room after classes.
Mr. Takahashi did?
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
高橋先生が？
Hikari said it was a lot of fun.
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, 楽しい[たのしい]:enjoyable/fun, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however
（悠子）
ひかりちゃん 言ってたよ
楽しかったって
He seems pretty spacey, but he's actually very caring.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 意外[いがい]:unexpected/surprising, 面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, 見[み]:looking/viewing, 見[けん]:view (of life, etc.)/outlook
ぼ〜っとしてるけど
あの先生 意外に面倒見いいよね
（ひまり）ふ〜ん
（悠子）何？
Hmm...
What?
Oh, nothing.
ううん:no|er, well, ...
（ひまり）ううん 別に
To tell the truth, I still don't trust Mr. Takahashi!
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 信用[しんよう]:confidence/dependence/credit, してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
（ひまり）
実をいうと
私は高橋先生をまだ信用していない
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, うっかり:carelessly/thoughtlessly/inadvertently
（高橋）
体だけだったから
うっかりガバッといっちまった
I got careless since it was just her body, and I hugged too hard.
町[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||, 気付く[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
町 気付いたかな？
I wonder if Machi noticed.
気付く[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise, 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train
気付いてるよな 普通
Yeah, of course she did...
（ひまり）あっ！
（高橋）ん？
（高橋）おう
Hey.
Hello.
（ひまり）どうも
教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom), 意外[いがい]:unexpected/surprising, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
教師って
意外と早く帰っていいんですね
I didn't know teachers were allowed to leave so early.
Oh, yeah...
わりと:relatively/comparatively, 遅く[おそく]:late, 残る[のこる]:to remain/to be left
ああ まあ… ひまりちゃんは
わりと遅くまで残ってるんだな
And I see you stayed pretty late, Himari.
I did. I like the library.
図書室[としょしつ]:library room, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
（ひまり）
そうですね 図書室が好きで
Come to think of it, I hear you did amazingly well on the last exams.
（高橋）
そういえば ひまりちゃん
テスト:test, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
この前のテスト
すごかったみたいだな
Th-Thank you.
ありがとう:Thank you/Thanks, ござる:to be
（ひまり）
あ… ありがとうございます
図書室[としょしつ]:library room, 勉強[べんきょう]:study|diligence|discount
（高橋）
いつも 図書室で勉強を？
You always study in the library?
Y-Yes, and I read books to refresh myself.
リフレッシュ:refresh (e.g. memory, one's spirits, etc.), 本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess
（ひまり）
えっ ええ…
あとリフレッシュで本を読んだり
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
（高橋）
そうか
ひかりとは全然違うな
I see.
You're nothing like Hikari, huh?
That was suspicious.
怪しい[あやしい]:suspicious/dubious|charming
（ひまり）
怪しい
He's always nice to my sister, but...
お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female
いつも お姉ちゃんに
よくしてくれてはいるけど…
ん？　どうした？
What's wrong?
N-Nothing...
いいえ:no/nay|well
いっ いいえ
Just worried that my sister's been bothering you.
迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
姉が ご迷惑をおかけして
いるんじゃないかと
生物[せいぶつ]:living things/creature|biology, 生物[なまもの]:raw food/perishables, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, 室[しつ]:room|wife (of someone of high rank)|scabbard|, 室[むろ]:greenhouse/icehouse/cellar, 涼む[すずむ]:to cool oneself/to cool off/to enjoy the cool air
（高橋）
ハハッ 生物準備室で
涼ませてやってるだけだ
I've been letting her cool off in the biology prep room.
Is that right?
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female, 実験[じっけん]:experiment, サンプル:sample/example/specimen
（ひまり）
どうだか 実は お姉ちゃんを
実験サンプルのように見てるんじゃ
Or are you actually looking at her as an experimental sample?
実験[じっけん]:experiment
（高橋）ああ 実験…
（ひまり）えっ？
Oh, the experiment.
I forgot to prepare one for tomorrow's class.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 授業[じゅぎょう]:lesson/class work/teaching, 準備[じゅんび]:preparation/setup/arrangements, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, 器材[きざい]:tools and materials/equipment and materials, 人数[にんずう, ひとかず]:the number of people|many people/a large number of people, 足りる[たりる]:to be sufficient|to be worth doing|to be sufficient
（高橋）
明日の授業の準備忘れてた
器材 人数分 足りるかな？
I hope I'll have enough materials for everyone.
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
まあ 明日でいっか
Well, I can do it tomorrow.
I'm overthinking this...
気にする[きにする]:to mind (negative nuance)/to care about/to worry, 過ぎる[すぎる]:to pass through|to pass (i.e. of time)|to have expired||, 過ぎる[よぎる]:to go by/to cross/to pass by, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひまり）
気にし過ぎね
デミ好きの先生でも
Even if he does love demis,
バンパイア:vampire, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
バンパイアの性質について
四六時中 考えているわけじゃ…
there's no way he thinks about the nature of vampires around the clock.
Oh, right!
（高橋）ああ そうだ
バンパイア:vampire, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition
バンパイアの性質について
聞きたいんだけどさ
I wanted to ask you something about the nature of vampires.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
（ひまり）
本当に考えてた！
He actually does!
Wh-What would that be?
なっ… 何でしょうか？
Hikari seems to have no problem chowing down on garlic,
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, ニンニク:garlic (Allium sativum), むしゃむしゃ:munch/crunch, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
ひかりはニンニクだろうと
むしゃむしゃ食べるみたいだが
バンパイア:vampire, ニンニク:garlic (Allium sativum), 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear, 伝承[でんしょう]:handing down (information)/legend/tradition
よく聞く“バンパイアは
ニンニク嫌い”という伝承
but the stories you hear assume that vampires hate garlic.
眉唾[まゆつば]:fake/counterfeit, 考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
あれは眉唾なのかどうか
考えてみたんだ
I was thinking about whether it was all fake.
（ひまり）はっ はあ…
R-Right...
バンパイア:vampire, 夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, 闇[やみ]:darkness|bewilderment|black-marketeering, 紛れる[まぎれる]:to disappear into|to do something under the cover of (confusion, etc.)|to be almost indistinguishable||, 襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit
（高橋）
バンパイアは夜
闇に紛れて 人を襲うという
They say vampires attack humans at night, under cover of darkness.
なぜだと思う？
Why do you think that is?
Uh, isn't it because they hate sunlight?
日光[にっこう]:sunlight, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe
（ひまり）
ああ…
日光を嫌うからじゃないですか？
十字架[じゅうじか]:cross/the Cross (of Christ), すがる:to cling to/to hang onto|to rely on, すがる:red-banded sand wasp (Ammophila sabulosa)|deer, 恐れる[おそれる]:to fear/to be afraid of
（高橋）
それだけで 十字架にすがるほど
恐れられはしないだろう
I don't think that makes them scary enough for people to carry crosses.
Some books say that vampires have very keen senses.
文献[ぶんけん]:literature/books (reference)/document, バンパイア:vampire, 感覚[かんかく]:sense/sensation/feeling, 鋭い[するどい]:sharp (blade)|sharp (pain)|perceptive|, 記述[きじゅつ]:description/descriptor
文献によっては バンパイアは
感覚が鋭いという記述もある
I think that's the reason.
理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
俺は これが理由だと思う
昼夜[ちゅうや]:day and night, 問う[とう]:to ask|to charge (e.g. with a crime)|without regard to|, 視力[しりょく]:eyesight, 感知[かんち]:perception/sensing/noticing, 聴力[ちょうりょく]:hearing ability
昼夜を問わない視力
人を感知する聴力
Sharp vision, even at night, hearing that can detect humans,
血[ち]:blood/consanguinity, 臭い[くさい]:stinking|suspicious|clumsy||, 臭い[におい]:odour/odor|aura, 嗅ぎ分ける[かぎわける]:to scent out/to discern, 嗅覚[きゅうかく]:sense of smell/olfaction
血の臭いを嗅ぎ分ける嗅覚
a sharp sense of smell to pick up the scent of blood.
暗闇[くらやみ]:darkness/the dark, 優位に立つ[ゆういにたつ]:to dominate/to prevail/to be superior to, 十分[じっぷん, じゅっぷん]:10 minutes, 十分[じゅうぶん]:plenty|division into ten|perfectly
暗闇の中で
人より優位に立つには十分だ
That's more than enough for an advantage over humans in the dark.
What does the sharpness of their senses have to do with garlic?
五感[ごかん]:the five senses, 鋭い[するどい]:sharp (blade)|sharp (pain)|perceptive|, ニンニク:garlic (Allium sativum), 関係[かんけい]:relation|participation|influence||
五感の鋭さとニンニクに
何か関係が？
ポイント:point, 嗅覚[きゅうかく]:sense of smell/olfaction, 鋭い[するどい]:sharp (blade)|sharp (pain)|perceptive|
ああ ポイントは嗅覚の鋭さ
Well, the key point is their sense of smell.
鼻[はな]:nose, 効く[きく]:to be effective|to do its work|to be possible to use, 過ぎる[すぎる]:to pass through|to pass (i.e. of time)|to have expired||, 過ぎる[よぎる]:to go by/to cross/to pass by, 臭い[くさい]:stinking|suspicious|clumsy||, 臭い[におい]:odour/odor|aura, 食べ物[たべもの]:food, 嫌う[きらう]:to hate/to dislike/to loathe
鼻が効き過ぎるがゆえに
臭いの強い食べ物を嫌う
Since their noses are so sensitive, they hate strong-smelling foods.
I think that's why vampires in legends hate garlic.
バンパイア:vampire, ニンニク:garlic (Allium sativum), 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear
それが“バンパイアは
ニンニクが嫌い”という
伝承[でんしょう]:handing down (information)/legend/tradition, 正体[しょうたい]:true character/true form|consciousness, 考察[こうさつ]:consideration/inquiry/enquiry
伝承の正体なのではないか
などと考察してみたんだが
I've been thinking about those things, but what's the real story?
どうだろうか？
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, 五感[ごかん]:the five senses, 鋭い[するどい]:sharp (blade)|sharp (pain)|perceptive|
ひかりは
五感が鋭かったりするのか？
Does Hikari have sharp senses?
Yes, that's quite accurate.
認識[にんしき]:recognition/awareness/perception, 間違い[まちがい]:mistake|accident|improper conduct (e.g. between man and woman), 五感[ごかん]:the five senses, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
その認識で間違いないと思います
姉の五感は すごいです
My sister's senses are incredible.
（高橋）おっ やった〜
Oh! All right!
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, むしゃむしゃ:munch/crunch, ニンニク:garlic (Allium sativum)
じゃあ ひかりは
なんで むしゃむしゃ ニンニクを？
Then, how can she eat so much garlic?
それは…
That's because...
She just isn't picky enough about her food.
好き嫌い[すききらい]:likes and dislikes/pickiness (about food)/choosiness, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
姉が
好き嫌いがなさすぎるからです
不安[ふあん]:anxiety/uneasiness/insecurity, 確認[かくにん]:confirmation/verification/validation
不安になって確認したんです
I got concerned and asked her if she was forcing herself to eat it.
無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
無理して
食べてるんじゃないかって
そしたら…
And she said...
It's fine, it's fine!
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
大丈夫 大丈夫
私 ニオイ きっついの好きだから
I love foods that smell really strong!
あ〜ん
ん〜！
外[そと, と]:outside|open air|other place, 外[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|
う〜ん
お外で言ってほしくはないな
I wouldn't want her to say that in public.
はい 本当に
You can say that again...
Lots of people who talk to me about my sister say
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
この手の話になると
よく言われます
she doesn't seem like a vampire,
バンパイア:vampire, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
“姉はバンパイアらしくない”
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 学生[がくせい]:student (esp. a university student), 学生[がくしょう, がくそう]:Heian-period student of government administration|Buddhist scholar|learning, 変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
“普通の女子学生と
変わらないじゃないか”と
that she's just like a normal high school girl.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 大層[たいそう]:very|extreme|splended|, 執心[しゅうしん]:devotion/attachment/infatuation
高橋先生は デミの性質に
大層 ご執心のようですが
You seem very interested in demis' natures,
あたり:hit|success, あたり:on the bank of/by the side of (e.g. a river, pond)|(in the) neighbourhood
そのあたりは どうですか？
so what do you think of that?
Do you think my sister doesn't seem like a vampire?!
バンパイア:vampire, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish, 思い[おもい]:thought|imagination|desire||
姉はバンパイアらしくないと
お思いですか？
Are you not that interested in her human side?
人間性[にんげんせい]:humanity/human nature
姉の人間性については
興味[きょうみ]:interest (in something)/curiosity (about something)/zest (for)
それほど
興味ありませんか？
Okay, I'll give you a straight answer.
ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly
そうだな ちゃんと言おう
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, バンパイア:vampire, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 即する[そくする]:to conform to/to agree with/to be adapted to, 行動[こうどう]:action/conduct/behaviour, あまり:remainder/rest|not very (with negative sentence)
確かに あいつはバンパイアの
性質に即した行動は あまりしない
It's true that she doesn't behave the way I'd expect a vampire to.
だが それで
But if you asked whether that makes her unlike a vampire,
バンパイア:vampire, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
バンパイアらしくないと言われると
それは違う
I'd say it doesn't.
Hikari does want to suck people's blood,
ひかり:skips-most-stations Toukai-line Shinkansen, ひかり:light|illumination/ray, 血[ち]:blood/consanguinity, 吸う[すう]:to smoke|to suck|to absorb|, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
ひかりは
人から血を吸いたい気持ちはあるが
but she settles for blood bags.
パック:pack, 我慢[がまん]:patience/endurance/perseverance
パックで我慢している
And even though she has a vampire's keen sense of smell,
バンパイア:vampire, 鋭敏[えいびん]:sharpness/keenness/sensitiveness, 嗅覚[きゅうかく]:sense of smell/olfaction, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, ながら:while/during|while
また バンパイアの鋭敏な嗅覚を
持ちながらなお
she loves foods with strong scents.
匂い[におい]:odour/odor|aura, 食べ物[たべもの]:food, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
匂いの強い食べ物が好き
That human side is what makes her like a vampire,
人間性[にんげんせい]:humanity/human nature, バンパイア:vampire, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
そういった人間性が
あいつのバンパイアらしさであり
個性[こせい]:individuality/personality/idiosyncrasy
人間としての個性だ
and it's what makes her unique.
It isn't how you're born that makes you "like" something.
らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish, 生まれる[うまれる]:to be born, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition
“らしさ”は
生まれ持った性質ではない
性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 踏まえる[ふまえる]:to be based on/to have origin in|to have one's feet firmly planted on, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
性質を踏まえて どう生きるかだ
It's how you live with what you are.
性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 理解[りかい]:understanding/comprehension/appreciation, 怠る[おこたる]:to be negligent in doing something/to shirk/to be off one's guard
だからといって デミの性質の
理解を怠っていいわけじゃない
But that doesn't mean it's okay to ignore a demi's nature.
The concerns unique to demis are caused by their natures.
特有[とくゆう]:characteristic (of)/peculiar (to), 悩み[なやみ]:trouble/troubles/worry, 必ず[かならず]:always/without exception/necessarily, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition, 起因[きいん]:cause/origin
デミ特有の悩みは
必ず性質に起因するからだ
You can't look at things in only one way.
物[もの, もん]:thing|one's things|things||, 物[ぶつ, ブツ]:stock/products|stolen goods, 見方[みかた]:viewpoint/point of view|way of understanding, 一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 方向[ほうこう]:direction/orientation|course (e.g. of action), 双方向[そうほうこう]:two-way/bidirectional/interactive, しかり:yes/yea|to be so, しかり:scolding
物の見方は 一方向ではダメだ
双方向でしかるべき
You should look from both angles.
特性[とくせい]:special characteristic/special quality/trait, 個性[こせい]:individuality/personality/idiosyncrasy, 見失う[みうしなう]:to lose sight of/to miss
デミの特性だけ見ていると
個性を見失う
If you just see traits unique to demis, you'll miss their individuality.
人間性[にんげんせい]:humanity/human nature, 悩み[なやみ]:trouble/troubles/worry, 原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source, たどりつける:to arrive at (after a struggle)/to finally reach/to find one's way to
人間性だけ見ていると
悩みの原因に たどりつけない
If you only see the human side, you won't understand their troubles.
Both are precious.
どちら:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 大切[たいせつ, たいせち]:important|beloved|careful, 大切[おおぎり]:large cut (e.g. of meat)|last piece of the day's programme/last act of a play, バランス:balance, 大事[だいじ, おおごと]:important/valuable|safe (Tochigi dialect)
どちらも大切だ
バランスが大事なんだ
What's important is balance.
That's what I think.
考える[かんがえる]:to think about|to ponder|to intend||
俺は そう考えている
音[おと, ね]:sound|note|fame|
（ひまり）
ぐうの音も出ない
I'm speechless.
信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in
信じてもいいかも
Maybe I can trust him...
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
あの 先生
Um, Mr. Takahashi...
うん？　何だ？
What's up?
Would you like to come to our house sometime?
今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, もらえる:to be able to receive/to be able to take|could you (give me)
（ひまり）
よかったら 今度
うちに来てもらえませんか？
Oh, I did, not long ago.
こないだ:the other day/lately/recently, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family
（高橋）
おお こないだ行ったぞ
家の前までだけどな
In front of it, anyway.
I'd like my parents to hear what you just said.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 両親[りょうしん, ふたおや]:parents/both parents
今の先生のお話
両親にも聞かせたくて…
（メールの受信音）
（高橋）そうか
Oh, okay!
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 親[おや]:parent|dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)|founder|, 親[しん]:intimacy|close relative|pro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.), 御[ご]:honorific/polite|honorific suffix, 御[ぎょ]:honorific affix|honorific prefix, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 伺う[うかがう]:to ask|to implore (a god for an oracle)|to visit|
実はな 俺も親御さんたちの話を
伺ってみたいとは思ってたんだ
Actually, I was thinking I'd like to talk to your parents, too.
先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy
（ひまり）先生…
（高橋）うん？
Mr. Takahashi...
Hmm?
By the way, I have a question for you!
ちなみ:association/link|pledge (esp. for marriage), 質問[しつもん]:question/inquiry/enquiry
（ひまり）
ちなみに質問なんですが！
What does hugging my sister let you learn?
行為[こうい]:act/deed/conduct
ハグとは
姉の何を知るための行為ですか？
Mr. Takahashi hugged me today!
He totally attacked me!
バンパイア:vampire, 性質[せいしつ]:nature/property/disposition
バンパイアの性質ですか？
Was it her vampire nature, or her human side?!
人間性[にんげんせい]:humanity/human nature
姉の人間性ですか？
Hugged? Attacked?!
襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit
（高橋）
ハグされた？　襲われた？
何言ってたんだ あいつは
What is she thinking?
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 勝手に[かってに]:arbitrarily/of its own accord/voluntarily
誤解だ ひまりちゃん
あいつから勝手に…
You've got it wrong, Himari! She's the one who—
屁理屈[へりくつ]:sophism/quibble/hair-splitting, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 教師[きょうし]:teacher (classroom)
（ひまり）
この 屁理屈(へりくつ)デミ好き教師〜！
You...
Rationalizing, demi-loving teacher!
I don't deny that, but still!
否定[ひてい]:negation/denial|NOT operation
（高橋）それは 否定しないが〜！
お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female
（ひまり）お姉ちゃん！
Sis?
Sister, are you oka—
お姉ちゃん[おねえちゃん]:familiar form of "older sister"|form of address for young adult female, だいじ:important/valuable|safe (Tochigi dialect), だいじ:letters in a title
（ひまり）お姉ちゃん だいじょ…
（ひかり）おりゃ〜！
誤解[ごかい]:misunderstanding, 生む[うむ]:to give birth/to bear (child)|to produce, メール:email
（ひまり）
で なんで
こんな誤解を生むメールを？
And why send me such a misleading message?
I'm sorry...
なさる:to do
（ひかり）ごめんなさい…
You were so late getting home, and I was bored here.
帰ってくる[かえってくる]:to return/to come back, 遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 暇[ひま, いとま]:spare time|time (e.g. time it takes to do something)|time off||
ひまり 帰ってくるの遅いから
家で暇で
I thought if I sent a message like that, you'd come home faster.
メール:email, 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
そういうメール送ったら
早く帰ってきてくれるかなって
まさか:by no means/never!|something unexpected, 先生[せんせい, せんじょう]:teacher|with names of teachers, etc. as an honorific|previous existence, 先生[シーサン]:boy, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
まさか 先生も一緒だったとは
I had no idea Mr. Takahashi was with you.
ハア〜
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, メール:email
別に普通に 早く帰ってきてって
メールしてくれれば そうするから
If you'd just sent a message asking me to hurry home, I would have.
Really? I love you, Himari!
大好き[だいすき]:loveable/very likeable/like very much
（ひかり）
本当？　ひまり 大好き！
抱きつく[だきつく]:to cling to/to embrace
（ひまり）抱きつかないでよ
Quit clinging to me!
♪〜
The events of a mysterious world,
Like the ones you hear of in fairy tales,
Are actually closer than you think
Just like the way you and I met!
When I stood up tall to gaze at
The familiar scenery outside my window,
Even days that felt like torture seemed precious somehow.
Stuck in my heart, I can't put them into words
How should I try to put these feelings into words?
Laughing over stupid things...
Getting mad over small details...
We'll keep carving these trivial moments into our hearts.
Sometimes I'm feeling sad...
But when I'm with you, I'm so happy!
We'll keep on building these irreplaceable moments,
And little by little, we'll come to understand one another.
〜♪
Next Time
The Little Snow Woman Is Cold
Next time on Interviews with Monster Girls:
次回[じかい]:next time (occasion), 亜人[アじん, あじん]:subhuman/demi-human|American (person), 語る[かたる]:to talk about|to recite|to indicate
（ひかり）
次回「亜人ちゃんは
語りたい」
The Little Snow Woman Is Cold.
雪女[ゆきおんな]:snow woman, 冷たい[つめたい, つべたい]:cold (to the touch)/chilly|coldhearted
「雪女ちゃんは冷たい」